<root>
    <top>/deployvirtualmachinesresponse</top>
    <command>deployVirtualMachine</command>
    <defaultresponses>jobid</defaultresponses>
    <params>
        <param>
            <name>serviceofferingid</name>
            <description>the ID of the service offering for the virtual machine</description>
            <required>true</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>templateid</name>
            <description>the ID of the template for the virtual machine</description>
            <required>true</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>zoneid</name>
            <description>availability zone for the virtual machine</description>
            <required>true</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>account</name>
            <description>an optional account for the virtual machine. Must be used with domainId.</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>diskofferingid</name>
            <description>the ID of the disk offering for the virtual machine. If the template is of ISO format, the diskOfferingId is for the root disk volume. Otherwise this parameter is used to indicate the offering for the data disk volume. If the templateId parameter passed is from a Template object, the diskOfferingId refers to a DATA Disk Volume created. If the templateId parameter passed is from an ISO object, the diskOfferingId refers to a ROOT Disk Volume created.</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>displayname</name>
            <description>an optional user generated name for the virtual machine</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>domainid</name>
            <description>an optional domainId for the virtual machine. If the account parameter is used, domainId must also be used.</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>group</name>
            <description>an optional group for the virtual machine</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>hostid</name>
            <description>destination Host ID to deploy the VM to - parameter available for root admin only</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>hypervisor</name>
            <description>the hypervisor on which to deploy the virtual machine</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>ipaddress</name>
            <description>the ip address for default vm's network</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>iptonetworklist</name>
            <description>ip to network mapping. Can't be specified with networkIds parameter. Example: iptonetworklist[0].ip=10.10.10.11&amp;iptonetworklist[0].networkid=204 - requests to use ip 10.10.10.11 in network id=204</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>keyboard</name>
            <description>an optional keyboard device type for the virtual machine. valid value can be one of de,de-ch,es,fi,fr,fr-be,fr-ch,is,it,jp,nl-be,no,pt,uk,us</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>keypair</name>
            <description>name of the ssh key pair used to login to the virtual machine</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>name</name>
            <description>host name for the virtual machine</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>networkids</name>
            <description>list of network ids used by virtual machine. Can't be specified with ipToNetworkList parameter</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>securitygroupids</name>
            <description>comma separated list of security groups id that going to be applied to the virtual machine. Should be passed only when vm is created from a zone with Basic Network support. Mutually exclusive with securitygroupnames parameter</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>securitygroupnames</name>
            <description>comma separated list of security groups names that going to be applied to the virtual machine. Should be passed only when vm is created from a zone with Basic Network support. Mutually exclusive with securitygroupids parameter</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>size</name>
            <description>the arbitrary size for the DATADISK volume. Mutually exclusive with diskOfferingId</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
        <param>
            <name>userdata</name>
            <description>an optional binary data that can be sent to the virtual machine upon a successful deployment. This binary data must be base64 encoded before adding it to the request. Currently only HTTP GET is supported. Using HTTP GET (via querystring), you can send up to 2KB of data after base64 encoding.</description>
            <required>false</required>
        </param>
    </params>
    <responses>
        <response>
            <name>jobid</name>
            <description>shows the current pending asynchronous job ID. This tag is not returned if no current pending jobs are acting on the virtual machine</description>
            <pack>8</pack>
        </response>
    </responses>
</root>